{
  "quizTitle":"Harry Potter Pop Quiz","topicID":"HP","questions":
  [
    {"id":"1","question":"Who is Harry Potter's godfather?","options":["Severus Snape","Remus Lupin","Sirius Black","James Potter"],"answer":"Sirius Black"},
    {"id":"2","question":"What year was the first film, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone, released in cinemas?","options":["2005","1999","2001","2003"],"answer":"2001"},
    {"id":"3","question":"Which future Batman actor played Triwizard Tournament entrant Cedric Diggory?","options":["Ben Affleck","Robert Pattinson","Christian Bale","Michael Keaton"],"answer":"Robert Pattinson"},
    {"id":"4","question":"Who was Minister for Magic during the first five films?","options":["Rufus Scrimgeour","Arthur Weasley","Cornelius Fudge","Kingsley Shacklebolt"],"answer":"Cornelius Fudge"},
    {"id":"5","question":"What was the name of the Hippogriff Harry and Hermione save from execution?","options":["Fawkes","Norbert","Buckbeak","Aragog"],"answer":"Buckbeak"},
    {"id":"6","question":"On which floor of Hogwarts was the forbidden corridor in The Philosopher's Stone?","options":["Fourth floor","Fifth floor","Third floor","Second floor"],"answer":"Third floor"},
    {"id":"7","question":"What was the name of the tree Harry and Ron crashed their car into?","options":["Forbidden Forest Oak","Elder Tree","Whomping Willow","Giant Sequoia"],"answer":"Whomping Willow"},
    {"id":"8","question":"Who did Killing Eve star Fiona Shaw play in the Harry Potter films?","options":["Bellatrix Lestrange","Molly Weasley","Petunia Dursley","Narcissa Malfoy"],"answer":"Petunia Dursley"},
    {"id":"9","question":"What village can Hogwarts students visit from their third year?","options":["Diagon Alley","Little Whinging","Hogsmeade","Godric's Hollow"],"answer":"Hogsmeade"},
    {"id":"10","question":"Who was Hermione's date at the Yule Ball?","options":["Cedric Diggory","Draco Malfoy","Ron Weasley","Viktor Krum"],"answer":"Viktor Krum"},
    {"id":"11","question":"What is the name of Voldemort's pet snake?","options":["Nagini","Slytherin","Naginiya","Basilisk"],"answer":"Nagini"},
    {"id":"12","question":"What flavour are Bertie Bott's beans?","options":["Chocolate","Every Flavour","Lemon","Strawberry"],"answer":"Every Flavour"},
    {"id":"13","question":"Which future Doctor Who played Barty Crouch Jr. in The Goblet of Fire?","options":["Matt Smith","David Tennant","Peter Capaldi","Jodie Whittaker"],"answer":"David Tennant"},
    {"id":"14","question":"What is the name of the building said to be the most haunted in Britain?","options":["Hogwarts Castle","Tower of London","Shrieking Shack","Buckingham Palace"],"answer":"Shrieking Shack"},
    {"id":"15","question":"What animal represents Hufflepuff house?","options":["Eagle","Badger","Serpent","Lion"],"answer":"Badger"},
    {"id":"16","question":"What is the name of Harry's mother?","options":["Molly","Martha","Petunia","Lily"],"answer":"Lily"},
    {"id":"17","question":"Which actor replaced Richard Harris as Dumbledore from the Prisoner of Azkaban onwards?","options":["Alan Rickman","Maggie Smith","Michael Gambon","Ian McKellen"],"answer":"Michael Gambon"},
    {"id":"18","question":"Which Weasley brother gets married in the Deathly Hallows Part 1?","options":["Charlie Weasley","Percy Weasley","Bill Weasley","Fred Weasley"],"answer":"Bill Weasley"},
    {"id":"19","question":"Which class has a different teacher every year?","options":["Potions","Defence Against the Dark Arts","Herbology","Transfiguration"],"answer":"Defence Against the Dark Arts"},
    {"id":"20","question":"Who did Game of Thrones actress Natalia Tena play in the Harry Potter films?","options":["Cho Chang","Luna Lovegood","Nymphadora Tonks","Ginny Weasley"],"answer":"Nymphadora Tonks"}
  ]
}